[MUSIC]
[似然值]
In this lecture we will
talk about likelihoods.
這一講介紹的是似然值
Likelihoods are a way to express
the relative evidence for
似然值呈現兩個假說間的相對證據力
one hypothesis over another hypothesis.
They can be very useful in themselves.
似然值的用處很多
But they are also underlying
a lot of Bayesian statistics,
至於似然值在貝氏統計學的用處
as we'll see in later lectures.
是下一講的主題
A likelihood gives you the function
of a parameter given the data.
似然值是資料函數的參數「L(θ)」
So when you've observed some data, you
can pull up the accompanying likelihood
從觀察資料中得出似然值函數
function and you can check how likely
each hypothesis that you might have is.
來評估不同假說得到支持的可能性
In this example, we mainly focus on
the binomial likelihood function.
以最簡單的二項似然函數為例
This is the easiest situation.
It's like flipping a coin and
假設你擲硬幣數次
then counting the number of
heads that you have observed.
記下正面出現的次數
This is the binomial likelihood function.
就會得到一條二項似然函數
I won't explain it in detail here, but
在此我不說明細節
而是當成作業
there's an accompanying assignment in
which we dive into the function and
請你以不同觀測值，計算出對應的似然值
calculate some likelihoods for different
of observations of number of heads.
請你以不同觀測值，計算出對應的似然值
For now, let's take a look at the
situation where we flip a coin ten times.
讓我們瞧瞧擲硬幣10次的情形
Eight of these ten times we find
that the coin comes up heads.
其中有8次硬幣正面朝上
We can calculate the likelihood of theta,
基於這些數據
我們已經可以計算似然值θ了
and theta in this case is a Greek letter
that explains the true hypotheses.
但是θ是指什麼呢？
首先是代表真實假說的希臘字母(讀音theta)
And in this case we might assume that the
true underlying number of heads that we
其次是指只要你擲夠多次硬幣，
觀察到正面硬幣的次數比值
will observe if we do this
in the long run is 0.8.
其次是指只要你擲夠多次硬幣，
觀察到正面硬幣的次數比值
So for the theta of 0.8, we can
calculate that the likelihood is 0.30.
所以代入函數，θ等於0.8會得到似然值等於0.30
But we can also calculate the likelihoods
for all sorts of different hypotheses.
除了θ等於0.8的似然值，還可以計算其他假設的似然值
Let's say that you have the idea that
the true value of the number of coin flips
如果你認為觀察到的正面硬幣枚數的機率為70%
in the long run is 70% or a theta of 0.7.
或是θ等於0.7。你該怎麼計算它的似然值？
The likelihood for this being true,
based on the data that we have observed,
切記似然值基於我們的觀測數據
eight out of ten coin
flips turned up heads.
要用「擲10次硬幣出現8枚正面朝上」的函數計算
The likelihood of the true
population effect being 0.7 is 0.23.
代入函數就會知道，θ等於0.7時
似然值等於0.23
The likelihood of a theta of 0.6 is 0.12.
θ等於0.6時
似然值等於0.12
So you can see it becomes less and
它離你的觀察值(θ等於0.8)越遠
less likely the farther away
you go from the observed data.
它的似然值也變得越小
Now these numbers are not very clear, so
至此我們有了比較清楚的圖像
let's take a look at
the likelihood function.
可以來談談似然函數(likelihood function)
In this graph, you can see
the likelihood function plotted.
這張圖描繪參數與似然值的函數關係
On the vertical dimension of this graph,
we have plotted the likelihood.
縱軸，代表似然值
橫軸，代表歡察次數比率θ
And on the horizontal dimension,
we have plotted theta.
縱軸，代表似然值
橫軸，代表歡察次數比率θ
All different versions
ranging from 0 to 1.
比率數值介於0到1之間
So the range of 0 to 1 means that we
will either always observe heads or
幾乎沒有「全是正面」或「毫無正面」的觀察結果
we'll never observe heads.
Now based on the data we have collected,
we already know that
依據收集到的資料可知
it's not possible that we'll never observe
heads or we'll never observe tails.
從未觀察到全是正面或全是反面的結果
Because eight out of ten
turned out to be heads.
由於十次之中最可能看到八次正面
So we've observed both values.
觀察結果應該有正有反
So the extremes are not possible, and
you can see that the likelihood here is 0,
所以最不可能觀察到的結果似然值等於0
it's very low.
代表不可能發生
The most likely true population parameter
of the number of coin flips based on
因為觀察得知θ等於0.8
我們就設定這個參數值最接近真正的母數
the data that we have is 0.8, because
this is exactly what we have observed.
因為觀察得知θ等於0.8
我們就設定這個參數值最接近真正的母數
So this is the maximum likelihood.
所以θ等於0.8有最大似然值
Based on the data that
we have in our hands,
因為根據手邊的資料
we can see that 0.8 is the most
likely true population parameter.
0.8最有可能是真實母數
But some of the values just around
it are also still quite plausible.
0.8附近的θ值也能描述硬幣的性質
So a value of 0.6 is still quite
probable in this case as well.
例如θ等於0.6也是蠻有可能的
These types of likelihood curves
were invented by Ronald Fisher,
上週介紹的費雪是第一個提出似然曲線(likelihood curves)的學者
I already said he was a really,
really smart guy.
我必須說他真的是個天才
And he invented these likelihoods when he
was only 22 years old and actually a 3rd
22歲時還是大三的他就提出似然曲線
year undergraduate student, so this sort
of testifies to his genius, I would say.
我認為這真的該歸於他的天份
Sometimes I wonder what have I been doing
the last couple of years, definitely
有時我捫心自問
我在大學畢業前能發明統計學的基石嗎？
not inventing something like this that's
a fundament of modern statistics.
有時我捫心自問
我在大學畢業前能發明統計學的基石嗎？
Now we can use the likelihood
under the null hypothesis and
現在，我們可以用虛無假設的似然值
the likelihood under
the alternative hypothesis
以及對立假設的似然值
to calculate something that's
known as the likelihood ratio.
來計算似然比(likelihood ratio)
So in the case of likelihood ratio,
we're taking the relative evidence for
似然比是虛無假設成立對比
對立假設成立的賠率(odds)
the one hypothesis, the null,
and the other hypothesis,
似然比是虛無假設成立對比
對立假設成立的賠率(odds)
the alternative, and we can calculate
the odds of one over the other.
顯示手上證據支持兩者的相對程度
Let's look at our example,
where we had eight out of ten coin flips.
拿一開始的例子來說,投了硬幣十次有八次正面
Now we need to compare two hypotheses, and
我們可以拿函數裡的任兩個θ
代表要比較的兩個假設
you're free to choose any two
values of theta that you want.
我們可以拿函數裡的任兩個θ
代表要比較的兩個假設
But one very logical value would be 50%,
0.5,
不過比較合理的一個數值是50%
the hypothesis that this is
a perfectly balanced and fair coin.
表示我們假設這個硬幣是絕對公平的
So this is the value that's plotted
at 0.5 on the horizontal axis.
所以代表這這個假設的數值是0.5
And you can compare this with any
hypothesis you had in advance.
你可以用這個值與你有興趣的所有假設比較
The alternative hypothesis I've
chosen here is the value 0.8.
我選擇的對立假設數值是0.8
This happens to be exactly the value
that we've observed in the data.
這個數值正是我們實際觀察到的
Eight out of ten coin flips.
十次之中有八次正面朝上
Now we're comparing this alternative
hypothesis that a true population
現在我們要比較的這個對立假設
設定真正的母數是0.8
parameter is 0.8.
現在我們要比較的這個對立假設
設定真正的母數是0.8
So 80% of the time this coin
will come up heads, and
表示投擲十次會有八次是正面
we'll compare it to the null hypothesis,
the value of 0.5,
而虛無假設的數值0.5
the idea that this is
a perfectly balanced, fair coin.
代表這個硬幣絕對公平的主張
Now we can already see in the graph
that the likelihood is much
從圖中可看到0.8的似然值
比0.5的似然值還高
higher at 0.8 than it is at 0.5.
從圖中可看到0.8的似然值
比0.5的似然值還高
But what we want to know is,
how much more likely?
但是我們想知道的是,有多少可能性?
And the likelihood ratio
gives us an idea of this.
似然比能給我們這個答案
It's basically dividing the likelihood
at 0.8 by the likelihood at 0.5.
基本上只要把0.8的似然值除以0.5的似然值
And in this case, this ratio is 6.87.
得到的似然比是6.87
So it's quite more likely that
the true population parameter is
所以母數是0.8的可能性是0.5的六倍多
0.8 compared to the ID that
the population parameters 0.5.
所以母數是0.8的可能性是0.5的六倍多
Now we can test any values that we want.
現在我們可以檢驗任何我們想比較的數值
Let say that in advance we still had
the same alternative hypothesis,
這個例子也是測試相同的對立假設
that this was a coin that would
come up heads 80% of the time.
就是這枚硬幣投擲十次會有八次正面
We still compare it to the probability
that this is a fair coin.
另一方面我們也認為這是一枚公正的硬幣
So these two hypotheses are being
compared, but now we have observed data
為了比較這兩個假設，我們重新收集資料
where the coin comes up heads
four times out of ten flips.
卻發現投這枚硬幣十次有四次正面
So we can see the shape of the likelihood
function is very different, and
所以似然函數的曲線改變了
in this case of course,
based on the observed data,
而且根據觀察的數據
似然值0.4的可能性最高
the likelihood of 0.4 is most likely.
而且根據觀察的數據
似然值0.4的可能性最高
We can still compare the ratio of
the likelihoods at 0.5 and 0.8,
以此計算0.5和0.8的似然比
and now we see that the value of 0.5 is
much more likely than the value at 0.8.
發現母數是0.5的可能性比0.8還高
So the hypothesis that this is a fair
coin is now much more likely than
所以這是一枚公正硬幣的假設
the hypothesis that this
is an unfair coin, and
比這是一枚不公正硬幣的假設更合理
that the true population parameter is 0.8.
真正的母數應該是0.5
(Daniel可能說錯)
Now when you calculate likelihood ratios,
there are two cutoffs of 8 and
似然比有兩個截止值為8和32
32 of these likelihood ratios which
are considered either moderately strong
之間的數值被認為顯示中等強度證據
evidence or strong evidence.
或強度證據
So in the previous examples, we could see
that in the first case, we had not yet
在擲硬幣例子裡，
第一種結果的證據強度(6.87)並未達到中等水準
moderately strong evidence for
the difference in the hypotheses.
在擲硬幣例子裡，
第一種結果的證據強度(6.87)並未達到中等水準
In the latter case, when we observed four
out of ten flips coming up heads, we can
第二種觀察到投擲硬幣十次有四次正面
see that this was very strong evidence for
the fair coin hypothesis compared to
表示這是枚公正硬幣的證據強度(37.25)超過水準
the alternative, that this was a coin
with 0.8 coin flips coming up heads.
遠高於這枚硬幣有0.8機率擲出正面的對立假設
So you see that likelihoods
are relative evidence for
所以似然值是對立假設與虛無假設
的相對證據強度
the alternative hypothesis
compared to the null hypothesis.
所以似然值是對立假設與虛無假設
的相對證據強度
It's important to realize that both of
these hypotheses might be quite unlikely.
但是你要了解兩者可能都是很難得到證據支持的假設
Let's look at an example.
我們來看這一個例子
Now here we flip the coin 100 times, and
現在投擲一枚硬幣100次
50 out of the 100 times,
the coin came up heads.
其中有50次正面朝上
Now, we are comparing two hypotheses here,
the one being that the true population
我們要比較的兩個假設，
其中一個設定母數θ是0.3
parameter is 30% heads in the long run,
so a theta of 0.3.
也就是持續投擲硬幣有30%正面朝上
The alternative hypothesis is that
the true population parameter is at
對立假設主張母數是0.8
theta of 0.8, so
we'll see 80% heads in the long run.
也就是持續投擲硬幣有80%正面朝上
When we compare these two
hypotheses against each other,
用這道函數比較這兩個假設
we can see that the hypothesis that true
population parameter is 0.3 is massively
可以看出假設母數是0.3比母數是0.8更有可能
more likely than the likelihood that
the true population parameter is 0.8.
可以看出假設母數是0.3比母數是0.8更有可能
And we find a ridiculously
high likelihood ratio.
這是因為得到一個很高的似然比
However, we can also see that
both these hypotheses are wrong.
但是也可以看到這兩個假設都是錯誤的
So even though the relative evidence for
the one hypothesis compare to the other
所以即使是一個假設比另一個假設的相對證據
hypothesis is extremely convincing, we
didn't find the true population parameter,
更有說服力, 觀察結果都沒有呈現真正的母數
which is actually just 0.5 in this case.
也就是投出正面的比率是0.5
So it's important to keep in mind that
likelihood ratios are relative evidence.
所以務必記住似然比是相對的證據強度
Now we can compare the likelihood under
the null hypothesis of a theta of 0.05 and
這個例子比較的虛無假設參數是0.05
對立假設參數是0.8
an alternative hypothesis of 0.8.
這個例子比較的虛無假設參數是0.05
對立假設參數是0.8
Now one way in which you can think about
你可以考慮應用這樣的似然比在你自己的資料分析
applying these likelihood ratios is when
you think about the outcomes of studies.
你可以考慮應用這樣的似然比在你自己的資料分析
Now, if you perform a study,
it's sort of like a coin flip.
如果你的研究很像觀察投擲硬幣的結果
You can either find a statistically
significant result, or not.
結果有可能是統計顯著，或者不顯著
So this is one of two options,
and it's a binomial probability.
兩種結果發生的機率都能用二項機率表示
So how often will you find
a significant result, and
表示有多少次實驗能觀察到顯著結果？
how often will you find
a non-significant result?
以及有多少次實驗能觀察到不顯著結果？
Well it depends on whether
the null hypothesis is true or
這與虛無假設主張為真或
the alternative hypothesis is true.
對立假設主張為真有關
When the null hypothesis is true,
we know that you'll find
虛無假設主張為真時，
似然值告訴你發現顯著結果的機率
a significant result that equals your
alpha level, which is typically 0.05%.
相當於一般設定的顯著水準，也就是0.05%
So this is a very good null hypothesis
in these likelihood ratios.
以似然比來看，這樣的虛無假設設定非常不錯
We can compare this with the probability
of finding significant results when
與真正有效果且發現顯著結果的機率比較
能顯出邏輯與證據的意義
there is a true effect.
與真正有效果且發現顯著結果的機率比較
能顯出邏輯與證據的意義
And in this case, this probability
depends on the statistical
所以用的統計檢定法的考驗力(power)也很重要
power that you have in your test.
Let's for now put it at 0.8, so
也就是這張投影片提到的0.8
80% of the time you'll find a significant
result because you had 80% power.
代表檢定有80%的考驗力，能發現顯著結果的機率
Now we can use the likelihood function
to compare the probability that we have
現在透過似然函數比較
虛無假設主張為真並有顯著結果的機率
observed a significant result
under the null hypothesis, and
現在透過似然函數比較
虛無假設主張為真並有顯著結果的機率
compare it with
the alternative hypothesis.
與對立假設主張為真並有顯著結果的機率
Let's say that we perform
three studies in a row.
假想一項研究連續做了三次
Now there are a number of outcomes
that could happen, of course.
投影片上的結果都有可能會發生
None of these studies
could come up significant.
有可能沒有一次研究出現顯著結果
You could find only one
significant effect, or two.
也有可能出現一次或兩次顯著結果
Or, if you're really lucky, three
significant results out of three studies.
也許你家裡祖上有德，三次都是顯著結果
Now let's calculate
the likelihood of finding two
現在拿三次有二次顯著結果的似然值來做些計算
out of three significant results.
When the null hypothesis is true,
this is pretty straightforward.
如果虛無假設主張為真，似然值的計算很簡單
The probability of finding a significant
effect when there's no true effect
代表沒有真正效果卻發現顯著結果的機率
is the alpha level, so
this is 0.05% of the time.
相當於顯著水準
也就是只有0.05%的實驗結果是顯著的
We multiply it by two significant studies.
似然值就是兩次顯著結果的相乘
So 5% times 5%.
就是5%乘以5%
And then we multiply it by the probability
of finding no significant effect.
再乘以其餘一次沒有顯著結果的機率
Well, if we have a 5% alpha level,
then the probability of finding
即然沒有效果卻發現顯著結果的機率是5%
相對沒有發現顯著結果的機率就是95%
no significant effect, if there's
no true effect, is actually 95%.
即然沒有效果卻發現顯著結果的機率是5%
相對沒有發現顯著結果的機率就是95%
So if you multiply these probabilities,
把這些機率相乘
5% times 5% times 95%,
we get the value of 0.0024.
也就是5%乘以5%乘以95%
得到的值為0.0024。
All right, so what happens if there
is a true effect to be observed, and
那麼如果真的有效果，
三次研究有兩次顯著結果的似然值該怎麼算？
we find two out of three
significant findings?
那麼如果真的有效果，
三次研究有兩次顯著結果的似然值該怎麼算？
Now let's assume that we have 80% power.
一開始已經設定考驗力是80％
You never really know, but
實際上很難得知真正的考驗力
(第三週課程說明)
you can check different levels of power in
the likelihood function when it's plotted.
但是似然函數能描繪各種程度的考驗力對應的似然值
But for now, let's take a look at 80%.
現在來看看考驗力80%的計算結果
So we find two significant results and
one nonsignificant result.
因為有兩次顯著結果與一次不顯著結果
If the alternative hypothesis is true,
this equals an 80% probability of finding
如果對立假設主張為真，
相當於有80％的機率能出現顯著結果
a significant result,
times an 80% probability of
如果對立假設主張為真，
相當於有80％的機率能出現顯著結果
finding a significant result, times a 20%
probability of making a type two error.
兩個80%相乘，再乘以20%的型二錯誤率
And if we now multiply these
probabilities, we get 0.128.
就會得到似然值是0.128
So we can calculate the relative
likelihood of observing this data,
所以接著能計算三次研究結果有兩次是統計顯著
two out of three significant results,
when either the null hypothesis is true,
虛無假設主張與真對比對立假設主張為真的似然比
or the alternative hypothesis is true.
Now based on these numbers, you can
already see that this outcome is much
根據計算結果(0.128/0.0024)
可以得知有真正效果的可能性
more likely when there is a true effect
than when there is no true effect.
高於沒有真正的效果的可能性
So, if we calculate likelihood ratio,
似然比是54
we see that it's actually
54 times more likely that
表示對立假設為真的可能性
是虛無假設為真的54倍
the alternative hypothesis is true than
that the null hypothesis this is true.
表示對立假設為真的可能性
是虛無假設為真的54倍
It's possible to find this pattern of
results when there is no true effect.
雖然現在的分析結果是沒有真正效果的發現
But it's massively more probable that
you'll find this pattern of results
但是更有可能是有真正效果的發現
when there is a true effect.
We can plot this likelihood function,
把這個例子繪製成似然函數
because you might not be convinced that
80% power is very likely in this case.
更能說服你，
有80%檢定力的分析的可信度有多高
Now if you look at this graph, we can
again see the likelihood function which is
圖中標示三次研究有兩次顯著結果的似然比是怎麼回事
plotted for
two out of three significant results.
圖中標示三次研究有兩次顯著結果的似然比是怎麼回事
I've indicated two points,
the 0.05 theta on the left,
請注意橫軸左側的0.05和右側的0.8
and the 0.8 theta on the right.
Now the 0.05 is the type one error rate,
or your alpha, so that's pretty fixed.
0.05表示型一錯誤率，或者顯著水準
是許多研究的通用設定
But maybe you feel like you might
have had lower power in your study.
不過你也許認為自己的研究沒那麼高的檢定力
And you can look at
the relative likelihood of
要檢查不同程度的檢定力
the outcome of two out of three studies
for any value of theta that you like.
發現三次研究有兩次顯著的似然比
The most probable situation, of course, is
that for exactly the result that we have
最可能的檢定力就是實際的狀況
observed, two out of three
significant results, meaning 0.666.
也就是三次之中有兩次顯著結果，正是0.666
For any of these values, you can see that
as long as you assume a decent level of
不論抓那個數值，只要考檢定力高於一定程度，
像是0.5
power, something higher than 0.5,
不論抓那個數值，只要考檢定力高於一定程度，
像是0.5
it's much more likely that there is a true
effect than that there is no true effect,
有真的效果的可能性
比沒有真正的效果的可能性高
even though we only observed two out of
three statistically significant results.
即使三次研究只有二次統計顯著結果
Now this is an important realization that
you can get by looking at these likelihood
由此我們學到重要的一課
似然函數能如何幫我們評估多次研究的結果
functions.
由此我們學到重要的一課
似然函數能如何幫我們評估多次研究的結果
Multiple studies should give mixed results
when the alternative hypothesis is true.
當對立假設主張為真
多次研究應該呈現顯著與不顯著的結果
And even when you have a decent level
of power, this will happen quite often.
即使檢定力沒有達到前例的水準
也應該有相似的發現
What's the likelihood of finding
three significant results in a row
如果檢定力有80%
三次研究都是顯著結果的似然值有多少？
when you only have 80% power?
如果檢定力有80%
三次研究都是顯著結果的似然值有多少？
I'm saying only, but
我再提醒一下
that's actually a pretty decent and
recommended level of power, right?
80%是有起碼品質的研究建議應維持的檢定力水準
(見1-3講)
So we can do the math, it's quite easy,
我們做點算術就能明白這項建議的道理
0.8 x 0.8 x 0.8 gives you
a likelihood of 0.51.
0.8相乘3次，得到0.51的似然值
So about 50% of the time,
when you have 80% power and
這表示只要對立假設主張為真，檢定力維持在80%
the alternative hypothesis is true, you'll
find three significant results in a row.
同樣的研究重覆數次，有50%的機率你會發現三次顯著結果
It means that almost 50% of the time, you
will get some version of mixed results.
另外50%的結果會是只有二次、一次、甚至沒有統計顯著
Either two out of three,
one out of three, or
另外50%的結果會是只有二次、一次、甚至沒有統計顯著
if you're unlucky, even zero out of three.
Even though there might be a true effect.
即使分析背後確實有真正的效果
Now this won't happen so often, but
all these outcomes are probable.
雖然不顯著不會經常發生，
但是任何分析結果都是有可能的
And the probability of mixed
result is almost 50% of the time.
多次研究存在至少一次不顯著結果的機率是50％
So this is important to realize,
when you're doing lines of research,
當你分析的研究資料是多次實驗資料
請謹記在心
you will not find consistently significant
results in all of your studies, and
所有研究結果至少有一次不顯著是很正常的
this is perfectly fine.
This is exactly what you should expect.
不該期待所有結果都是統計顯著
Now in this graph I've plotted a lot
of lines that are relevant for
這張圖描繪有四項研究的資料
分析結果顯著與否的排列組合及似然值
a situation where we perform four studies.
這張圖描繪有四項研究的資料
分析結果顯著與否的排列組合及似然值
When we perform four studies, we can
either observe zero significant results,
分析結果會是都沒有顯著結果
or one, or two, or three, or four.
或者有一次，二次，三次，或四次顯著結果。
So each of these curves plots one
of these likelihood functions,
每一條曲線代表一種分析結果的似然函數
given the data that we've observed.
Now what I want to point out here is,
這些曲線顯示發現至少一個不顯著結果的機率有多高
again, the massive probability
of finding mixed results.
這些曲線顯示發現至少一個不顯著結果的機率有多高
And we can see this for
all the curves for one, two, three, or
把每條曲線對應至少一個不顯著結果的似然值標出來
four out of four results, where the
likelihood is highest for mixed results.
把每條曲線對應至少一個不顯著結果的似然值標出來
And that's actually this area.
可以標出這塊區域
So when we perform four studies, and the
theta, which means the power that we have,
這塊區域表示四次研究要找的母數
運用的分析方法檢定力
is somewhere between 0.2 and 0.8,
so between 20% power and 80% power.
在20%到80%之間的似然值
Then finding mixed results is actually the
most probable outcome of a line of four
不論四次之中顯著結果有多少，
各種結果出現的機會是差不多的
studies.
不論四次之中顯著結果有多少，
各種結果出現的機會是差不多的
Now we've seen that likelihood ratios
allow you to express the relative
這一講學到似然比如何表示
虛無假設與對立假設的相對證據強度
evidence for the null hypothesis
compared to the alternative hypothesis.
這一講學到似然比如何表示
虛無假設與對立假設的相對證據強度
And this can be very useful in itself.
是相當有用的分析工具
For example, we applied this to
the probability of finding significant or
像是評估一組研究發現顯著或不顯著結果的機率
non-significant results
in a set of studies.
像是評估一組研究發現顯著或不顯著結果的機率
And we've seen that it's
actually quite likely
由最後一個例子學到
that you'll observe
a mix of significant and
即使對立假設主張為真
non-significant results, even when
the alternative hypothesis is true.
分析結果有顯著與不顯著是很正常的
Likelihoods also underlie
Bayesian statistics.
似然值也是貝氏統計的基礎
So knowing likelihoods is also
a good stepping stone to move on
了解似然值也是學習貝氏統計的入門磚
to Bayesian statistics,
which we'll do in future lectures.
欲知詳情，請見下一講
[MUSIC]